[Music]
hi everyone this is RI welcome to trien
tasa Advanced Training as you all know I
already published 53 YouTube videos
covering basic intermediate and advanced
level Concepts so from couple of videos
onwards I've started teaching you some
realtime scenarios where you might
encounter different types of obstacles
and how can we solve those obstacles
while automating your test cases so this
is our obstacle 12 in terms of real time
scenarios and this is our lesson 54 in
terms of overall trient tosar training
so in this obstacle I'm going to teach
you how can we solve an obstacle where
you need to interact with XML engine web
engine and then file engine we need to
load the XML file and we need to create
an XML file and then we need to scan an
XML file to solve this
obstacle please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank
you so this is our 12th obstacle the
obstacle name is B fast automate and
which is categorized
as hard so let us go for it let us first
understand what is the obstacle that we
need to solve
for so click the button Load Books to
load an XML structure of books to the
text
area click the load books now an XML
structure of books will be loaded in the
text area search through the XML and
find the ISBN off book titled testing
computer
software here you can see this is one
book the title of the book is this and
the corresponding ISBN number of the
title of the book is this so this way
you need to search
for testing computer software book title
and you need to copy the corresponding
ISBN number and enter this ISBN number
to the text box here you need to enter
this ISBN number into the text box but
you need to enter the ISBN number of a
specific book titled testing computer
software so how can we solve for this
let us go back to trient
tasa so before we start solving the
problem
let me explain the strategy how we are
going to solve the challenge so first
what we are going to do we are going to
use web engine to interact with this
button so that we can load the
XML and then once I load this
XML what I'm going to do I'm going to
use the file
engine to create a file and store store
this loaded
XML into that file store means and write
this loaded XML into a file what is the
file I'm going to create I'm going to
create do XML
file and
then I'm going to use XML engine to scan
the XML that we stored in our system
then I'm going to search for the title
of the book testing computer software by
using
constraint action mode and then I'm
going to store this ISBN into a buffer
so that I can print that ISBN number
into this buffer so that means we are
using total three different types of
engines web
engine file engine and XML engine so let
us go to our tric
toas as usual we going to scan all the
objects of
[Music]
application under the folder called
obstacles right click on this folder
select scan and select
application this is my application click
on
scan here I would like
to save the object related to this
button Load Books also I would like
to capture object of this particular box
where XML is
loading and then this edit box where
I'll be entering the ISBN number which
is this one so I captured all three of
them and all three of them are uniquely
identified so I don't have any conflicts
and now let us rename this module with
the obstacle
number copy this
number paste it here now let us save
this let us save all these objects and
close the X scan so if you go back to
your trient tasa so this is my latest
obstacle that we captured load books
books ISBN of testing computer software
so what I'm going to do here I would
like to
create a new folder
here what I'm going to do
here I'm going to create a new folder so
let me create a subfolder under
obstacles let me call this as the same
obstacle name that
we captured right now and then I'm going
to move this particular module under
this sub folder okay why I'm doing I'll
you'll get to know why I'm doing you'll
get to know okay so right now under
obstacles folder I have one module here
okay so now let's go back to our test
case section right blue color section
right click and create a new test
case and name this with the same
obstacle name double click on this test
case so now what I would like to do I
would like to start creating our test
steps for this test
case first I'm going to drag this module
and drop it
here and let me name this as
load this test let me name this test
step as
load
XML
structure so what I'm going to do here
first we need to click on this load
books button right for that simply enter
X here and your action mode is
input what it does it to load the XML
structure once you load the XML
structure I need to now create
one file XML file and I need to write
this particular content right to write
this content here I would like to
capture the content here I'm going to do
I need to capture this XML right into a
buffer for that let's one thing here
bore
XML content I'm creating bore XML
content as a buffer and then I'm going
to store this entire text into a
buffer okay so now we stored this
content into your buffer now we need to
use another method where we need to
create an XML file for that what I'm I'm
going to do control
T and here I'm going to say create we
can use read and create file I'm not
using Create XML file instead of I'm
using pbox read create
file so here what I'm going to do I'm
going to name this
as create XML
and write
content and what is the directory where
you would like to store let's say I
would like to store in this
directory let's take the path of this
directory and put it here and then what
is the file name I would like to name
this as books do
XML and then what is the text that you
would like to write here I would like to
write the text of this one which is
buffer right so how to call the buffer
open curly braces capital B open Square
braces
bore
XML
content close Square braces close curly
braces okay so just to make sure I'm
going to copy this entire buffer and
then I'm going to paste it here because
I should not have any spell mistakes
right so this is my buffer I'm writing
the content that I captured in this
buffer and then overwrite true I'd like
to overwrite the content if I run this
particular test case again and again
okay so let me run this particular test
case now and see what happens okay run
this so loaded and then it created an
Exel XML file so what I'm going to do
here now let's go back here okay it's
clicked on Load Books right now let's go
back to the path where we specified here
this is our books. XML let's open this
and
see the
content so you can see here this is the
content this is our first book this is
our second book
this is our third
book right we are looking out for this
book see testing computer
software and we need to capture ISBN of
this particular testing computer
software which is 107
3645 and this ISBN number need to be
typed need to be typed here okay so
let's close this one now okay so we are
successfully created creating we are
successfully creating the XML file that
is required okay now our next step is to
scan the XML whatever the XML that we
created here right in this location we
need to scan that XML for that let's go
to module section
again here under this folder I would
like to scan see this is our obstacle
folder okay
so here right click and then select scan
here I don't want to select the
application instead I would like to
select more and here select file scan
select this and then it's going to ask
you to select the file that you would
like to
scan I'm going to select the
corresponding
file so here this is my books. XML is
the file open this one so this will scan
the XML and it creates a module here you
can see here there is a resource and
then there is a catalog books under book
you have this particular book repeated
node under book you have author title
prize ISBN number right so we scan this
one
now let's go back to our test case now
so before I start using this model
module there is another step that we
need to follow what is that one we need
to open the XML see whenever you would
like to read the XML that we stored in
the system first you need to open the
XML file right for that control
T open XML file here open create XML
file select this
one and here what is the resource name
I'm going to name this as
XML file XML file I'm going to name this
as XML file what is the path the path of
the XML that we are storing this is the
path right
let's so this is the path let's select
this
path copy
this and paste it here
SL
books do XML
right this is your entire path now once
you open the XML now let us start using
this one what we need to do we need to
filter ISBN related to one specific book
title correct for that let's drag this
and drop it
here here what I'm doing Search for the
book related to testing computer
software right cop Cy this one so let's
go back here what I'm going to do here
I'm going to start
using the constraint option here
constraint method or action mode how so
if you see here this is my title right
I'm pasting the title of this particular
book and I'm going to use action mode as
constraint what it does it's going to
look for the book title testing computer
software and it filters out all other
options it takes this and then I would
like to capture the ISBN of this
particular book title right here I'm
going to store the content into your
buffer called
ISBN okay here as soon as you find
testing computer software book title
take this
ISBN number and store that into a buffer
called ISBN buffer and now once I get
the buffer I need to enter that buffer
into edit box right for that again we
need to start using the same module this
one track this and drop into your test
case this is our last step I'm going to
rename this as enter ISBN
number okay here scroll down and this is
your edit box right I'm going to call
this
buffer open curly braces B open Square
braces
ISBN close Square Braes close curly
braces so
done so we are done automating this
entire scenario let me explain what we
did again okay first we captured a
module with all the objects from this
particular page web page and here by
using the same module I created a test
step to click on this button and then
I'm buffering this entire content into a
buffer this buffer right and then
I am creating an XML called books. XML
and then I'm writing that
XML content which we stored in this
buffer into this
file done now I'm opening the same XML
that we
created and then by using XML scan I
have
captured the objects or the
XML
resources into a module I'm using the
same module to filter out the title of
the book testing computer software by
using the action mode
constraint and as soon as I get this
title I'm capturing the ISBN number of
the title into a buffer called isbl and
then again I'm using the same
module that we stored all these objects
right and here I'm
just typing the ISBN number that I
stored in the buffer from the
XML so now let
us change the work state workstate as
completed save this test case and now
let us run this test case right click
and run in
scratchbook so it says it is failing
let's go back and see what is failing
okay so
here either a resource or a transition
has to be specified book request so if
you see here we named the resource as
XML file right this one I need to use
the same resource see when I when you
open the XML file
I have named the resource resource as
XML file so now you need to use the same
resource name here as well when you
are trying to filter out the title with
the book name right so that resource
name is missing that's why we are
getting error message
as resource see either resource or trans
have to be specified so I have not
specified the resource that's why I
specified the resource that we provided
here now let's save this and run this
particular test case one more
time perfect see it entered 181
5763 let's verify this again okay let's
go back to our
XML open books XML
what is our book title testing computer
software what is the ISBN number 18157
63 go back
here 181
5763 that means we are able to capture
the ISBN
number of the book titled as
software book tit titled as testing
computer
software so if you have any queries
leave your leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries so this is very important
concept where we touched three different
types of engines web engine file engine
and XML engine and we also covered how
can we scan the XML and then how can you
search for a particular parameter within
the XML
[Music]